[siren wailing]
Oh.
[Jane]
What's the fuss?
[Cho]
Slept through Lisbon's
briefing in the van, didn't you?
Like a baby.
[Cho]
Yeah, the victim's
name is Kristin Marley.
She worked at the State Capitol
for some lady senator.
Went missing three days ago.
Rumor is she was
having an affair
'with the senator's husband.'
- My bet. She's a jumper.
- I hope not.
If she's a jumper,
job's done.
Yeah, the senator's husband
dumps her
she wants to make him feel bad,
she comes out here..
[whistles]
...splat.
Don't talk that way.
Okay, not splat. Bam.
There's nothing worse than
suicide. Human life is sacred.
When someone takes
their own life, it's a tragedy.
Sacramento PD's
handing the case over to us.
Let's go talk
to the coroner.
Shall I recap
the case, sleepyhead?
Kristin Marley,
lady senator's aide
rumored romance
with the senator's husband.
Very good.
Oh, I trained myself
to hear
and take in information
while asleep.
- The others told you?
- Yes, they did.
[male #1]
At this point,
there's no way to determine
what happened
to the victim, Agent Lisbon.
I-I simply can't help you.
Well, can you tell
how long she's been dead?
[scoffs]
Couldn't possibly
given the evidence available.
Well, do you think it was
a homicide or a suicide?
- 'Couldn't say.'
- 'What's your guess?'
I'm not in the habit
of, of guessing.
Please don't touch
the decedent.
Y-you detectives always
want the instant answers.
What I do is science.
Science will...uncover the truth
but she will be precise,
methodical and take her time
before she renders
her decision.
Wonder if science can remove
the stick from his butt.
- I heard that.
- You're right. We want facts.
Fortunately, we have them.
Oh, we do?
In abundance.
You're the consultant
that pretends
to read minds, aren't you?
No. I don't pretend
to read minds.
Idoread minds.
But don't we all?
Look at Lisbon.
You can see
what she's thinking.
No kidding.
And I can see what
you're thinking right now.
Uh, I-I was thinking that
you, sir, are a bumptious fool
and I was wondering
exactly what training
in forensic pathology you have.
Ah, but right before that,
you were wondering
whether you would choose Lisbon
or Van Pelt as your concubine
in that little fantasy kingdom
you like to visit sometimes.
What? I do not.
Oh, and-nd you're right.
I-I know nothing
of forensic pathology.
'But agent Van Pelt..'
...she might offer...her theory.
Or I might not.
- Look at her feet.
- I did.
And what question
presents itself?
- Where's her other shoe?
- Exactly.
[Cho]
'It wasn't
up on the bridge.'
It could be in her car.
Even if it was,
why would she walk to
the middle of the bridge
with one shoe on?
- Why would she do that?
- Bingo.
There's no need
to be patronizing.
So she must have been carried.
She didn't kill herself. She was
murdered, then dropped over.
Or thrown over still alive.
Better than suicide.
It's...a theory.
It's lovely to meet you, doc.
You're a horse's ass,
but you mean well.
- I'll be in the van.
- Oh.
My apologies, sir.
Cho, tell the Sacramento PD
that it's a homicide.
Rigsby, Van Pelt, see what
the sheriff's department
got in their investigation.
[Rigsby]
Alright.
[theme music]
Kristin had been interning
here for about nine months.
She came in at the start
of the last session
right out of college.
I liked her. She was sweet,
young, in a good way.
- Who did she work for?
- Senator Melinda Batson.
'She's an up-and-comer
from the Central Valley.'
Please put that down.
Anything to the rumor
that Kristin was having
an affair
with Batson's husband?
Elliott Batson.
He's Melinda's chief of staff.
We've heard the rumors.
Everyone denies it.
There's no evidence
anything happened.
The media
seem to think there is.
You wanna get me started
on what they believe?
Frankly, when you've worked
here as long as I have
you hear a lot of stories
about wild behavior.
Most of them aren't true.
[amplified]
Except the ones that are.
[microphone feedback whines]
Whoa.
'Sorry.'
Hello.
Hello. Hello. Hello.
I've issued a statement, and
I'm not taking any questions.
We're not press.
We're CBI.
Agent Teresa Lisbon,
Patrick Jane.
Right. Sorry. You called.
Melinda Batson.
This is my husband Elliott.
Hi.
Tsk. Tough day around here.
Is this Kristin's desk?
- Yes.
- Mm.
Come inside.
Jane.
- Care to join us?
- I'll be right there.
Anything unusual
about Kristin's behavior
the day she disappeared?
No, she was, uh, cheerful.
Finished work, left at 6:00,
I think, uh..
- A little after 6:00.
- After 6:00 then.
Did she say
where she was going?
- No.
She...was having trouble
with her family.
It was her stepmother, right?
Her natural parents are dead..
and for some reason her
stepmother called
a bunch of times that day.
Did Kristin tell you
what it was about?
- No.
No. I...I was surprised.
I thought they were estranged.
What was your relationship
to Kristin, Mr. Batson?
Oh, please. Please. We know
where you're going with this.
- Melinda--
- No.
Let's just haul the trash
out in the open.
You want to know if she and
Elliott were sleeping together.
Were you?
Never. It's a rumor.
That's all.
Rumors usually happen
for a reason.
- Well..
- I'll give you the reason.
Politics.
You want to take a female
politician down a few notches?
Throw mud on her marriage.
Where were you the night
Kristin was killed?
Here. I was
on a conference call.
With a trade delegation
from Taiwan.
We talked until after 11:00.
I was with him
the whole time.
[clears throat]
We'll be married
three years this October and..
...today's news excepted, uh,
we've never been happier.
That's hard to believe.
What does that mean?
Well, there's nothing going on
between you right now.
Excuse me. What?
I'm sorry. I-I meant sexually.
No heat. Right?
I think we're done here.
[Jane]
'You'd think a politician
would have thicker skin.'
You accused them of lying
about their sex life
and you're surprised
they're upset?
Oh, come on.
You're buying that happy talk?
Really? Uh-oh.
- Agent Minelli, sir.
- Agent Lisbon.
I asked him down.
Uh, Walter Crew,
Melinda Batson's dad.
You're agents, uh,
Jane and Lisbon?
- Yeah, we are. Hi.
- Hi.
Sorry to track
you down like this.
I asked Virgil here
to introduce me to the team
handling the poor
Marley girl's case.
Walter has been a friend
of the CBI for some time.
He was an extremely influential
legislator for what, 20 years?
Twenty six, but who's counting?
Anyway, I'm old news now.
The only thing I lobby for
is a good tee time.
Why the interest
in the poor Marley girl's case?
Interest? I liked her.
Yeah, met her
in Melinda's office.
She was good people.
Came from a tough background.
'Didn't let that stop her.'
I know how difficult it is
to get straight answers
from the people
in that building there.
If you have any problems,
you just let me know.
- I can still knock heads.
- Oh, we'll be fine.
Just let me know.
- Virgil.
- Walter.
- Take care.
- 'Sir.'
I hate walks, Lisbon. I know
they're healthy. I don't care.
Put me in a chair,
I'm a happy man.
But when Walter Crew
asked me to stroll with him
down to the Capitol,
I say, "Of course, Walter."
- You get my drift?
- I do.
Step carefully.
I want daily reports.
Oh, and, uh, how did
the Batson interview go?
- Oh, that was very exciting.
- What did he do?
Nothing that can't be repaired.
[Carmen]
'Teresa, nice of you
to drop by.'
I know I'm late. I'm sorry.
Late is an interesting word
in this context.
You were
supposed to be here..
...forty two minutes ago.
I know. The point is,
I'm here now.
We're supposed to talk,
so let's talk.
I have another patient
scheduled in eight minutes.
I can talk fast.
This is the third time
you've been late.
What can I say?
Lot of people getting killed.
Can I get a coffee?
[sighs]
Do you know why
counseling is mandatory
for CBI agents who've been
involved in a shooting?
Because nobody would come
if it was voluntary?
And that's why
it remains mandatory..
...until I sign
and file this form.
- See you next week.
- This is unnecessary.
I'm fine.
I'm not traumatized.
A man pointed a gun at you.
A man who intended
to kill you.
Fortunately,
Jane shot him first.
It doesn't matter.
You went from thinking
you were going to be killed..
'...to watching a man die.'
Two of the most wrenching
experiences we can have.
And you went
through them in seconds.
You don't think
that affected you?
No.
You really want to keep
seeing me, don't you?
Next week...on time.
Fine.
Wow.
There's a stain on the ceiling
that looks like Elvis
but today it looks
more like a...basset hound.
Someone call the media.
It's a miracle.
Or maybe
someone's moved my couch.
Cho.
Did you move my couch?
No. Why would I?
Excuse me.
Did you move the couch?
[foreign accent]
I had to, uh,
change a light. Problem?
No, no, no. Can you help me
move it back, please?
I got a thing, I...thanks.
Just up there.
I think it's this way.
Just a little.
[grunts]
That's it.
Let me just try..
Perfect. Thank you.
Elvis is back.
Anything on the stepmom?
Her name is Charlotte McAdoo.
She called Kristin 11 times
in the two days
before she disappeared.
Any idea what that was about?
No, but her son Harlan
had been picked up
on a carjacking charge.
He posted bail
the day Kristin disappeared.
'Claimed he had nothing
to do with the carjacking.'
'Said he was with Kristin
when it happened.'
He used Kristin as his alibi?
How bad is Harlan?
Well, mostly car theft,
some assault.
What did Charlotte
have to say about that?
She won't answer her phone,
won't call back.
We're heading out
to talk to her.
Shouldn't we be looking
for Kristin's lover?
Who? Elliott Batson's alibi
checked out
and there's no sign
she was seeing someone else.
- 'We've checked.'
- Well, not enough.
She was an immature romantic
looking for escape
and adventure.
She was having an affair.
We searched
her place thoroughly.
She kept the affair well hidden.
Well, of course.
It's an adventure
because it's a secret.
But I expect
she'll tell us who it was.
I'll bite. How?
[clears throat]
Check this out.
She was a collector.
She kept sand from every
beach she ever went to.
She would have kept a memento
of her lover, something small.
I bet she kept it in
a fancy jewelry box
the kind with a figurine
on the lid.
There was a fancy jewelry box
like that in her bedroom.
- A ballerina.
- Ballerina. She's the type.
But we checked it. There's
nothing in it but cheap jewelry.
Did you check
in the secret compartment?
The secret compartment
either on the bottom
or one of the sides.
They usually have one.
It's worth taking a look.
Fine.
Forget about Bosco.
[Jane]
'He's got something.'
Yeah, he's got Red John,
and we don't.
No. No, he's got something new
on the case. New evidence.
How can you tell?
It's clear as can be.
I'll be right back.
Jane, Red John
belongs to Bosco now.
I don't like it either, but
you'll have to deal with it.
Do you want a coffee?
I'm gonna bring you a coffee.
I need copies of each of these
sent over to division.
'What's he doing in there?'
He said you told him
to wait in there.
[sighs]
We'll finish later.
- Get away from my desk.
- Where'dyougo?
I've been here
almost half an hour.
And stop hacking my passcodes
and stop hustling my people.
It's not doing you
any good, you know.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
What'd you get on Red John?
And what makes you think
I got anything?
Folder.
You moved it
when you saw me, protected it.
It's the one thing
you'd protect from me.
It's the cover-up
that gave you away.
- Huh.
- What is it?
It's none
of your business, so go.
You need
to understand something.
Red John doesn't make mistakes.
He doesn't leave clues.
If you have new evidence, it's
because he wants you to have it.
The question
isn't what does it mean?
It's why did he give it to you?
That's deep.
Tell me what it is.
I can help you.
Have you ever seen
a crack addict
when they're begging for a hit?
You got that same look
in your eye that they get.
Oh. You've got me
all figured out.
[cell phone rings]
Hey, Van Pelt.
Did you get it?
There's a secret compartment,
just like you said.
- And what was in it?
- Nothing. It's empty.
Huh...alright.
Bad news, huh?
No, not at all.
It's like you said, it's
the cover-up that gave you away.
You're an addict, Jane.
You need help.
- You're making a mistake.
- You can go.
[Rigsby]
I got tickets to the Kings game
tomorrow night. You wanna go?
- I'm going out.
- Who with?
The niece of that shopkeeper
we met on that Red John thing.
Oh, finally.
Took you long enough.
- 5B?
- Yeah.
Well, we talked on the phone.
She's nice.
- We'll see how it goes.
- I expect a full report.
- In your dreams.
- Hey, I got you that number.
- You owe me.
- No.
- Charlotte McAdoo?
- Yeah.
We need to talk to you
about your stepdaughter
Kristin Marley.
You know that Kristin's dead,
right, Charlotte?
What about it?
I guess
you're pretty broken up.
She wasn't my kid. I'm not
the huggy type. Sue me.
If you didn't like Kristin
why'd you make all those calls
right before she disappeared?
- Don't remember.
- It was a week ago.
I'm old.
My memory's bad.
Did it have something to do
with your son Harlan?
What about Harlan?
He used Kristin as an alibi
when he was arrested.
But Kristin told Sacramento PD
she hadn't seen Harlan
for months.
Were you asking Kristin
to change her story
and lie an alibi
for her stepbrother?
No, that's crazy.
- Where is Harlan?
- 'I don't know.
'I haven't seen him for days.'
Okay. Thanks for your time.
That's...that's it?
We'll see ourselves out.
Thank you.
[whispers]
You think Charlotte
smokes filtered and unfiltered?
Not if she's got a visitor.
Bathroom or closet?
- Bathroom.
- I think closet.
- You wanna bet?
- What do I get if I win?
I pay for lunch next week.
I win, you tell me
about your date.
That's enough time.
- Hey, Harlan.
- Oh, crap.
Harlan, were you
in the bathroom or the closet?
- Closet. Wh--
- I told you.
- We didn't bet.
- Yes, we did.
No law against
being in a closet.
No, Harlan, but it is
kinda suspicious.
- You got no right to hold me.
- We're just talking.
Alright, what do you
want to talk about?
Kristin Marley,
when did you see her last?
- What happened to her?
- You tell us.
Well, I got nothing to say
about her.
You must be mad that
she didn't back your alibi
on the carjacking charge, huh?
First of all...that arrest
was completely bogus.
And, B, that stuck-up bitch
don't get
what the word family means, so..
What is that?
Family's supposed to help
when you're down.
But she gets a job
in the Capitol
with some big money friends,
and pow
she's too good
for the people she grew up with.
She don't get what the word
family is all about, you know?
Didn't. She's dead.
Yeah.
That's too bad.
Did you have
any contact with Kristin
after you posted bail, Harlan?
- No.
- None?
That's what I said.
It's funny,
'cause our tech guys
have been going through
her cell phone.
There's some deleted
texts on it.
Four of them were from you
the day she disappeared.
Well, that's what you call
a-a glitch, computer thing.
You were threatening Kristin to
get her to lie for you, right?
- Didn't say that.
- I could see why you'd do it.
You're facing serious time.
You arresting me?
You got no right
to hold me if you ain't.
You're not under arrest.
But you are out on bail,
and that can be revoked
if the judge thinks
you're not being cooperative.
Do you want a soda, Harlan?
I want chips.
If he took Kristin's body to the
bridge, he put her in his trunk.
It's worth taking a look.
I'll call the district attorney.
If Harlan hears
we're looking at his car
he'll be out the door before
the warrant comes through.
We're gonna make him
want to stay.
'Van Pelt.'
You're taking over
the McAdoo interview.
I'm totally ready for that. I
can get him to confess to this.
Yeah, maybe.
The main thing is, you keep
him in there long enough
for us to search his car.
Be friendly.
He thinks he's a player.
He'll eat it up.
What do you mean,
be friendly?
Need a map?
Good luck.
Hey...I heard Bosco cleaned
your clock this morning.
Well, that's one interpretation.
I get it. It's tough to have
Red John taken away like that.
Bet you'd give a lot
to know
what they're saying
in Bosco's office.
Yeah.
Yeah, I would.
You gotta let it go, man.
Forget about the jewelry box.
You missed one.
- So what?
- Actually, I didn't.
I'm pursuing an independent
line of investigation.
Gonna crack
this case in 24 hours.
I think we might be
ahead of you this time.
Hi, Harlan.
I'm agent Van Pelt.
Special agent Lisbon asked me
to take over the interview.
Why?
She's busy
with something else.
So I've looked through
your file and it's, uh..
...it's very..
What?
Well..
I don't think you had
anything to do with this crime.
Thank you.
That's what I've been saying.
It's just a big
misunderstanding, I'm sure.
Yeah. You got that right.
But let's fill out the forms,
so everyone's happy, okay?
Mmm. Chips.
[crunching]
So...let's make a time line
of everywhere you've been
since Kristin disappeared.
Okay.
- You want another?
- Mm.
[doorbell rings]
[Jane]
'These all pictures
of your daughter?'
[Walter]
'Yes, they are.'
[Jane]
'Well, it's surprising
there's not more'
'pictures of you.'
Given your standing, that is.
What, me talking
to a bunch of famous windbags?
Had those. Took 'em down.
Waste of space.
- Thank you.
- No, my days are over.
Melinda has got the future.
She could go far, very far,
if she listens to me.
Now what did you want
to talk about?
[sighs]
How long were you sleeping
with Kristin Marley
before she was killed?
[scoffs]
What makes you think I was?
You're a politician.
Ambitious. Narcissistic.
Addicted to the love
of strangers.
She was beautiful,
impressionable
no doubt flattered
by your attentions.
And you're not
the sort of man
to deny yourself
an object of desire.
I'm married 38 years, Mr. Jane.
[chuckles]
As I said.
Uh, even if
what you say is true
and I'm not saying it is
what does that have to do
with poor Kristin's murder?
Blackmail or something like it.
The business adultery leads to.
Ah...but...even if I am
what you say I am and..
...I'm not saying I am..
...wouldn't I have faced
a situation like this before..
...and handled it
without killing anybody?
- It's a good point.
- 'Mm.'
- I'll think about that.
- Please.
Mm.
Anything else?
What? Mm? Sorry?
Well, whoever it is, I'll have
the killer by the morning.
So, uh, you should act
accordingly.
- Thank you for your time.
- You're welcome.
[instrumental music]
[Cho]
You think Harlan
ever cleans out his car?
So where you taking the
shopkeeper's niece for dinner?
I'd rather not talk about it.
- Why not?
- It's private.
Oh, come on.
Let's talk about somethin' else.
I'll call technical services.
They can pop that lock
in 20 seconds.
It'll take 'em
two hours to get here.
It took you two hours
to open the door
last time you tried this
and we had to pay
for the busted window.
Fluke.
If I had a date,
I'd tell you about it.
[scoffs]
Yeah.
I would tell you anything
you wanted to know.
Okay, you ever gonna man up
and make a move on Van Pelt?
- Fine. Don't tell me.
- Right.
[grunts]
Hey. Check this out.
Wasn't the other one of these
on Kristin Marley's foot?
I'll call Lisbon.
Kristin's shoe was
in your trunk.
No. No way.
Uh-uh.
You want to tell us
how it got there, Harlan?
I don't know.
Maybe you put it there, huh?
You have no alibi for the night
of Kristin's disappearance.
I told you.
I was with my mom.
She was concealing you
when we went to pick you up.
- It's not gonna cut it.
- You were mad at Kristin.
- A little, but--
- You threatened her.
No.
Okay, I mean, a-a little,
but come on.
I-I wouldn't hurt her for real.
That's not much
of a story, Harlan.
[whispers]
I thought you believed me.
You were wrong.
[chuckles]
You know what? The hell
with this. I'm outta here.
Not quite yet.
- Oh, you're gonna stop me?
- Yeah.
- Did you make the arrest?
- I did.
Ah, victory is yours.
Yes, it is.
What?
Oh, nothing.
- Come on.
- No. No.
I'm still waiting.
Throwing the body off
the bridge was a smart move.
Good chance the coroner
would declare it a suicide.
Do you really think
Harlan McAdoo
would come up with that?
Dumb people can come up
with smart ideas
and smart people
can come up with dumb ones.
Eh, true.
I'll have the real killer
here in 12 hours or so.
- What are you talking about?
- You'll see. Bye.
Jane.
Hey, boss, you want me to send
McAdoo down to be arraigned?
Not yet. Sit on him.
See if he comes up
with something useful
once he calms down.
Well, obviously,
you've got to get it out of
committee before..
- Mr. Jane.
- Hi. Don't mind me.
What are you doing?
- Hard at work, on the case.
- I don't understand.
We got a call from agent Minelli
saying that an arrest
had been made,
Kristin's stepbrother.
Nope, nope, nope. Wrong guy.
How can that be?
Simple miscarriage of justice,
happens all the time.
What does that mean?
It means I have to find
the real killer.
The real killer? How?
Oh, Kristin was a collector.
Ergo, the identity of Kristin's
killer will be in her things.
How can you be sure
it's there?
Oh, I'm sure.
Mr. Jane, this isn't acceptable.
First you accost my father--
Oh, I wouldn't use
the word accost.
And now you're
ransacking my office.
- Calm down, Melinda.
- I won't calm down.
I thought
we'd put this behind us.
Not much
of a campaign slogan.
"Batson, so tough on crime, she
puts the innocent behind bars."
Do what you have to do.
W-we'll help in any way we can.
Great. Thank you. There's
a couple of boxes right there.
If you could just,
uh, grab one each
and follow me to my car.
[Minelli]
'Lisbon, didn't you arrest
McAdoo?'
[Lisbon]
'Yeah, we did.'
DA says you haven't
sent him down to be arraigned.
We've 48 hours to do that.
We still have some loose ends.
- What, what loose ends? Him?
- No.
What are you doing?
No, don't tell me.
I want this off my desk.
Get McAdoo to the DA tonight.
How hard is Crew
leaning on you?
- He's not.
- Then who's doing it for him?
- No one.
- Is this my case, sir?
Yes, but--
Then it's my decision
as to when the suspect is
handed over to
the District Attorney, right?
If McAdoo isn't
in the DA's office
first thing tomorrow morning..
...this becomes
a different conversation.
[sighs]
- You won't regret this.
- I already do.
[cricket chirping]
[phone rings]
[Lisbon]
'Hey, this is Lisbon.'
'Leave a message.
I'll call you back.'
[beep]
I found what I was looking for.
I don't want to risk taking it
out of the office
so I'm gonna put it in the top
right hand drawer of your desk.
When you get this, call me.
[door opens]
"Ah ha."
[foreign accent]
Oh. Y-you startled me.
Uh..
I'll...I'll just
get out of your way.
- Stand still. Turn around.
- Huh? Whoa. Whoa.
What is this?
Who are you
and who are you working for?
I work for the building.
I clean. I clean.
Oh, you're not a cleaner.
Look at this place. It's a mess.
You're the fixer.
You've been listening in
on our conversations.
Huh? What's that? That's one
of the bugs you placed.
I found it
in the overhead light.
When I told Van Pelt to go
and check out the jewelry box
you overheard
and you went there first.
And it was you that placed
the shoe in McAdoo's trunk.
- I'm on the cleaning crew.
- Oh, really?
I'm new.
You can call my supervisor.
'Marty, uh..'
Marty, uh, Toretta, huh?
- Call him up right now.
- No.
Wake him up.
I got no idea
what you're talking about here.
We're talking about
accessory to murder
conspiracy, obstruction.
'Who hired you?'
Murder?
Oh, I-I don't feel too good.
- Can I sit? Can I--
- Oh, take a seat.
Thanks.
[American accent]
Alright. Oh, no, no. No.
- Calm. Are you calm?
- Sure.
Alright, now, I want you
to lift your gun out
with two fingers
and slide it across the floor.
Now, get your cuffs.
This isn't gonna work.
The door.
Hook yourself up.
Toss the keys.
[keys jingle]
Now you and I are
gonna walk out here.
Sure.
It's a little stroll.
[indistinct radio chatter,
door opens]
[door squeaking]
Find out where he goes.
- Uh, no, I think--
- Go, now. Go.
Oh.
- Ma'am.
- Keys, please.
There. Yeah.
[tires screeching]
[intense music]
[footsteps approaching]
So, Agent Lisbon, here we are.
What's this about?
This is Art Cavalleri.
He's the private investigator
one of you hired
to wiretap and obstruct
our investigation.
Really?
He's agreed to talk in exchange
for leniency.
'I called you down here
to offer you the same deal.'
Well, that's very nice of you.
You can discuss it
with my attorney.
- Melinda?
- I have nothing to say.
Even if you had nothing to do
with Kristin Marley's murder..
'...with what Cavalleri
is saying'
'about the conspiracy
and the cover up'
you're all gonna do
a lot of time in prison.
- I don't need to hear anymore.
- W-wait. I-I do.
What kind of leniency
are we talking about here?
- Elliott.
- Depends, Mr. Batson.
What do you know?
I need an assurance
that any charges
related to the murder
will be dropped.
You got it, as long
as you didn't have
anything to do with the murder.
If you'll excuse us,
I want some private time
with my family right now.
Mr. Crew, stay there.
Go on.
[Jane]
'Oh, come on.
Spit it out, man.'
The marriage is a sham.
She's gay. You're the beard.
It was kind of obvious
from the start.
I had an arrangement
with Melinda Elliott.
Don't.
I agreed to marry Melinda
in exchange for..
'...certain
financial considerations.'
Batson, we had a deal.
Did that deal
include time in prison?
I-I don't think so.
So it was your own people
that started the rumor
about you and Kristin to hide
her affair with Melinda.
Yes.
I'm sorry, Melinda.
Kristin broke it off
shortly before she disappeared.
Melinda was upset.
And were you with Melinda
the night Kristin disappeared?
No. I didn't see her
until late that night.
She was...a mess.
But she wouldn't
tell me what had happened.
Kristin had something
hidden in her apartment.
- A...memento, I guess.
- Lovers' memento.
Cavalleri had found it,
but we took it out of his car.
It could be a W,
but I think it's an M.
'You and your father were both
having an affair with Kristin.'
No.
- I--
- Melinda.
Ihad a relationship
with Kristin.
Heseduced her.
Took her..
...the way he's taken women
his whole life.
- I was trying to make a point.
- You were what?
- I was trying to show you--
- What?
That she was just another girl.
That she was just
another trashy little girl.
You thought you were in love,
but she was just having a fling.
He believed that
you were giving away
a very bright political career
because of some strumpet.
What happened that night?
Melinda,
every day you don't talk
'is another day
you're on the news.'
I knew Kristin
was seeing someone..
...but I didn't know who it was.
So I followed her..
...and that's when
I saw my father.
[exhales deeply]
After he left,
I went into her apartment.
She had these stone bookends.
'I grabbed one.'
Next thing I knew,
Kristin was on the floor.
It just...happened.
And then I did what
I always do when I'm in trouble.
I called daddy.
He said he knew someone
who could fix it.
Ah, the fixer.
You can let Cavalleri go now.
[whispers]
Watch.
Oh, my God.
He's dead.
Yeah.
You abused a corpse
to get a confession.
Used. Used a corpse.
There's no Ab.
I'm appalled. I'm..
I don't know what to say.
Sir, it's not like
we killed him.
His neck was broken
in the crash.
- We got a confession.
- Suppose you didn't.
Suppose you'd been wrong.
Have you any idea
of the vastness
of the crapstorm
that would follow?
It would blot out the sun.
Sir, Crew and Batson
manipulated us
into arresting
the wrong person.
They bugged our offices
and subverted our case.
I don't think we did
anything wrong.
I think
we should be commended.
[scoffs]
Congratulations. You finally
got her to drink the Kool-Aid.
Check yourself, agent.
All of you.
Well, I thought
that went pretty well.
Great. Yeah.
Highlight for me
was definitely your speech.
Passionate. Articulate. Strong.
Whatever.
Hmm.
Hey, good work with McAdoo,
you know, keeping him here.
Yeah.
You know...if boss
had given me a chance
I think I could have
gotten him to confess.
Sure, if he wasn't,
you know, innocent.
If it wasn't
for that small fact
I'm sure you'd have
taken him to town.
Thanks.
You have any plans
for tonight?
Home. TV.
Well...have fun.
You, too.
You're gonna die alone.
- 'Uh, sir..'
- Morning.
Sir, you can't go in there.
No, it's okay.
I come in peace.
- Great color on you.
- Y-you..
- Go away.
- Just give me a minute, please.
I-I want you, and I want your
team to know...that I got it.
I got the message.
I got it.
The Red John case...belongs
to you.
- You're gonna leave us alone?
- Yeah, that's right.
- I don't believe that.
- I bought you doughnuts.
'The international
law enforcement'
symbol of friendship.
I-I am trusting you
to catch Red John.
I'm counting on it.
We will catch him.
Thanks.
Good hunting.
Hicks, take that away.
Take it far away.
Take it out of the building.
God knows what he put in there.
You got it.
Alright, let's go over
the most recent forensics.
There are two short,
linear incised wounds
that are extremely superficial.
'They involve the anterior
surface of the right wrist'
'which measures 0.8 inches.'
[male #2]
'Okay, you got it.
[Bosco]
'Don't tell the local guys
what it's for.'
[male #2]
'Yeah, no worries.'
[Bosco]
'Just say you're following up
on something.'
'I want to keep this
on the down low for now.'
'Now, what else did you get
from handwriting analysis?'
[male #3]
'We've had two guys look at it.
One local, one from DC.'
'And of course, they agree
on pretty much nothing.'
[Bosco chuckles]
'Figures.
What did the DC Guysay?'
[theme music]